<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<quiz_level><quiz><id>pmp1</id><type>radio</type><question> Which of the following is an advantage of centralized contracting?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Gives easier access to contracting expertise</option1><option2>Increases company expertise in contracting</option2><option3>Gives more loyalty to the project</option3><option4>Allows a contracts person to work on a single project</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp2</id><type>radio</type><question> Risks will be identified during which risk management process(es)?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Quantitative risk analysis and risk identification</option1><option2>Risk identification and risk monitoring and control</option2><option3>Qualitative risk analysis and risk monitoring and control</option3><option4>Risk identification</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp3</id><type>radio</type><question> The highest point of Maslow&apos;s hierarchy of needs is:</question><answer>4</answer><option1>physiological satisfaction.</option1><option2>attainment of survival.</option2><option3>need for association.</option3><option4>esteem.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp4</id><type>radio</type><question> Who is ultimately responsible for quality management on the project?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Project engineer</option1><option2>Project manager</option2><option3>Quality manager</option3><option4>Team member</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp5</id><type>radio</type><question> A heuristic is best described as a:</question><answer>4</answer><option1>control tool.</option1><option2>scheduling method.</option2><option3>planning tool.</option3><option4>rule of thumb.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp6</id><type>radio</type><question> If earned value (EV) = 350, actual cost (AC) = 400, planned value (PV) = 325, what is cost variance (CV)?</question><answer>4</answer><option1>350</option1><option2>-75</option2><option3>400</option3><option4>-50</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp7</id><type>radio</type><question> A project manager has just been assigned to a new project and has been given the preliminary project scope statement and the project charter. The first thing the project manager must do is:</question><answer>2</answer><option1>create a project scope statement.</option1><option2>confirm that all the stakeholders have had input into the scope.</option2><option3>analyze project risk.</option3><option4>begin work on a project management plan.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp8</id><type>radio</type><question> You are taking over a project during the planning process group and discover that six individuals have signed the project charter. Which of the following should most concern you?</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Who will be a member of the change control board</option1><option2>Spending more time on configuration management</option2><option3>Getting a single project sponsor</option3><option4>Determining the reporting structure</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp9</id><type>radio</type><question> The project manager is making sure that the product of the project has been completed according to the project management plan. What part of the project management process is he in?</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Planning</option1><option2>Executing</option2><option3>Monitoring and controlling</option3><option4>Closing</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp10</id><type>radio</type><question> The WBS and WBS dictionary are completed. The project team has begun working on identifying risks. The sponsor contacts the project manager, requesting that the responsibility assignment matrix be issued. The project has a budget of U.S. $loo,ooo and is taking place in three countries using 14 human resources. There is little risk expected for the project and the project manager has managed many projects similar to this one. What is the next thing to do?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Understand the experience of the sponsor on similar projects.</option1><option2>Create an activity list.</option2><option3>Make sure the project scope is defined.</option3><option4>Complete risk management and issue the responsibility assignment matrix.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp11</id><type>radio</type><question> Risk tolerances are determined in order to help:</question><answer>1</answer><option1>the team rank the project risks.</option1><option2>the project manager estimate the project.</option2><option3>the team schedule the project.</option3><option4>management know how other managers will act on the project.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp12</id><type>radio</type><question> A project manager is employed by a construction company and is responsible for the furnishing of the completed building. One of the first things that the project manager for this project should do is to write a:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Work breakdown structure.</option1><option2>Budget baseline.</option2><option3>Project charter.</option3><option4>Project plan.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp13</id><type>radio</type><question> Your company has an emergency and needs contracted work done as soon as possible. Under these circumstances, which of the following would be the helpful to add to the contract?</question><answer>3</answer><option1>A clear contract statement of work</option1><option2>Requirements as to which subcontractors can be used</option2><option3>Incentives</option3><option4>A force majeure clause</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp14</id><type>radio</type><question> The &quot;halo effect&quot; refers to the tendency to:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>promote from within.</option1><option2>hire the best.</option2><option3>move people into project management because they are good in their technical fields.</option3><option4>move people into project management because they have had project management training.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp15</id><type>radio</type><question> A project manager is trying to complete a software development project, but cannot get enough attention for the project. Resources are focused on completing process-related work and the project manager has little authority to properly assign resources. What form of organization must the project manager be working in?</question><answer>1</answer><option1>Functional</option1><option2>Matrix</option2><option3>Expediter</option3><option4>Coordinator</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp16</id><type>radio</type><question> All of the following are characteristics of a project EXCEPT:</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Temporary</option1><option2>Definite beginning and end</option2><option3>Interrelated activities</option3><option4>Repeats itself every month</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp17</id><type>radio</type><question> A team is using a fishbone diagram to help determine what quality standards will be used on the project. What part of the quality management process are they in?</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Perform quality control</option1><option2>Perform quality assurance</option2><option3>Quality planning</option3><option4>Variable analysis</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp18</id><type>radio</type><question> The equivalent of cost reimbursable contracts is frequently termed:</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Back charge contracts.</option1><option2>Fixed price contracts.</option2><option3>Progress payment contracts.</option3><option4>Cost plus contracts.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp19</id><type>radio</type><question> A buyer extends a formal invitation that contains a scope of work that seeks a response that will describe the methodology and results that will be provided to the buyer. This is called:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Invitation to bid.</option1><option2>Request for information.</option2><option3>Request for proposal.</option3><option4>Request for bid.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp20</id><type>radio</type><question> A project manager must have some work done by an outside contractor. This work has a great deal of risk associated with it, and it has become very difficult to find a contractor willing to take on the job. Which of the following types of contract would offer the greatest incentive to the contractor?</question><answer>1</answer><option1>Cost plus percentage of cost as an award fee</option1><option2>Cost plus fixed fee</option2><option3>Cost plus incentive fee</option3><option4>Firm fixed price</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp21</id><type>radio</type><question> Purchasing insurance is considered an example of risk:</question><answer>2</answer><option1>mitigation.</option1><option2>transfer.</option2><option3>acceptance.</option3><option4>avoidance.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp22</id><type>radio</type><question> A cost performance index (CPI) of 0.89 means:</question><answer>4</answer><option1>at this time, we expect the total project to cost 89 percent more than planned.</option1><option2>when the project is completed we will have spent 89 percent more than planned.</option2><option3>the project is only progressing at 89 percent of that planned.</option3><option4>the project is only getting 89 cents out of every dollar invested.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp23</id><type>radio</type><question> In the matrix management organization, which of the following is true?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>The project manager is responsible for employee skills improvement.</option1><option2>The functional manager is responsible for employee skills improvement.</option2><option3>The project manager is responsible for the employee.s annual appraisal.</option3><option4>The employee is responsible for his or her own skills improvement.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp24</id><type>radio</type><question> Your program manager has come to you, the project manager, for help with a bid for her newest project. You want to protect your company from financial risk. You have limited scope definition. What is the BEST type of contract to choose?</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Fixed price (FP)</option1><option2>Cost plus percent of cost (CPPC)</option2><option3>Time and material (T&amp;M)</option3><option4>Cost plus fixed fee (CPFF)</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp25</id><type>radio</type><question> The project management process groups are:</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Initiating, planning, expediting, and control.</option1><option2>Plan, organize, develop, and control.</option2><option3>Plan, do, observe, commit.</option3><option4>Initiating, planning, executing, controlling, and closeout.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp26</id><type>radio</type><question> In which project management process group is the detailed project budget created?</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Initiating</option1><option2>Before the project management process</option2><option3>Planning</option3><option4>Executing</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp27</id><type>radio</type><question> Which of the following conflict resolution techniques will generate the MOST lasting solution?</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Forcing</option1><option2>Smoothing</option2><option3>Compromise</option3><option4>Problem solving</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp28</id><type>radio</type><question> Decomposing the major deliverables into smaller, more manageable components to provide better control is called:</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Scope planning.</option1><option2>Scope definition.</option2><option3>Scope base lining.</option3><option4>Scope verification.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp29</id><type>radio</type><question> Any numbering system that is used to monitor project costs by category such as labor, supplies, or materials, for example, is called:</question><answer>1</answer><option1>Chart of accounts.</option1><option2>Work breakdown structure.</option2><option3>Universal accounting standard.</option3><option4>Standard accounting practices.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp30</id><type>radio</type><question> Which of the following is NOT an input to the initiating process group?</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Company processes</option1><option2>The company culture</option2><option3>Historical WBSs</option3><option4>Project scope statement</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp31</id><type>radio</type><question> Workarounds are determined during which risk management process?</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Risk identification</option1><option2>Quantitative risk analysis</option2><option3>Risk response planning</option3><option4>Risk monitoring and control</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp32</id><type>radio</type><question> A person who is involved in or may be affected by the activities or anyone who has something to gain or lose by the activity of the project is called a:</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Team member.</option1><option2>Customer.</option2><option3>Stakeholder.</option3><option4>Supporter.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp33</id><type>radio</type><question> Quality is:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>meeting and exceeding the customer&apos;s expectations.</option1><option2>adding extras to make the customer happy.</option2><option3>the degree to which the project meets requirements.</option3><option4>conformance to management&apos;s objectives.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp34</id><type>radio</type><question> A schedule performance index (SPI) of 0.76 means:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>you are over budget.</option1><option2>you are ahead of schedule.</option2><option3>you are only progressing at 76 percent of the rate originally planned.</option3><option4>you are only progressing at 24 percent of the rate originally planned.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp35</id><type>radio</type><question> Contract closure is different from administrative closure in that contract closure:</question><answer>1</answer><option1>occurs before administrative closure.</option1><option2>is the only one to involve the customer.</option2><option3>includes the return oiproperty.</option3><option4>may be done more than once for each contract.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp36</id><type>radio</type><question> During the full life cycle of the project, a plot of the project.s expected expenditures will usually follow a characteristic ..S.. shape. This indicates that:</question><answer>4</answer><option1>There is a cyclic nature to all projects.</option1><option2>Problems will always occur in the execution phase.</option2><option3>There are high expenditures during closeout.</option3><option4>The bulk of the project budget will be spent in the execution phase.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp37</id><type>radio</type><question> An output of administrative closure is the creation of:</question><answer>1</answer><option1>project archives.</option1><option2>a project charter.</option2><option3>a project management plan.</option3><option4>a risk analysis plan.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp38</id><type>radio</type><question> A temporary endeavor undertaken to create a new product or service is called a:</question><answer>2</answer><option1>New product development.</option1><option2>Project.</option2><option3>Program.</option3><option4>Enterprise.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp39</id><type>radio</type><question> An example of scope verification is:</question><answer>1</answer><option1>Reviewing the performance of an installed software module.</option1><option2>Managing changes to the project schedule.</option2><option3>Decomposing the WBS to a work package level.</option3><option4>Performing a benefit-cost analysis to determine if we should proceed.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp40</id><type>radio</type><question> What conflict resolution technique is a project manager using when he says, &quot;I
cannot deal with this issue now!&quot;</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Problem solving</option1><option2>Forcing</option2><option3>Withdrawal</option3><option4>Compromising</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp41</id><type>radio</type><question> Approved corrective action is an input to:</question><answer>2</answer><option1>scope control and scope verification.</option1><option2>direct and manage project execution and integrated change control.</option2><option3>develop project management plan and develop project charter.</option3><option4>develop project management plan and schedule development.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp42</id><type>radio</type><question> A group of related projects that are managed in a coordinated way that usually include an element of ongoing activity is called a:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Major project.</option1><option2>Project office.</option2><option3>Program.</option3><option4>Group of projects.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp43</id><type>radio</type><question> To control the schedule, a project manager is reanalyzing the project to predict project duration. She does this by analyzing the sequence of activities with the least amount of scheduling flexibility. What technique is she using?</question><answer>1</answer><option1>Critical path method</option1><option2>Flowchart</option2><option3>Precedence diagramming</option3><option4>Work breakdown structure</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp44</id><type>radio</type><question> A project manager has assembled the project team, identified 56 risks on the project, determined what would trigger the risks, rated them on a risk rating matrix, tested their assumptions and assessed the quality of the data used. The team is continuing
to move through the risk management process. What has the project manager forgotten to do?</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Simulation</option1><option2>Risk mitigation</option2><option3>Overall risk ranking for the project</option3><option4>Involvement of other stakeholders</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp45</id><type>radio</type><question> Configuration management is:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Used to ensure that the description of the project product is correct and complete.</option1><option2>The creation of the work breakdown structure.</option2><option3>The set of procedures developed to ensure that project design criteria are met.</option3><option4>A mechanism to track budget and schedule variances.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp46</id><type>radio</type><question> A rough order of magnitude estimate is made during which project management process group?</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Project planning</option1><option2>Project closing</option2><option3>Project executing</option3><option4>Project initiating</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp47</id><type>radio</type><question> The breakdown structure the lowest level of the breakdown for the project manager is called the:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Activity.</option1><option2>Task.</option2><option3>Work package.</option3><option4>Cost account.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp48</id><type>radio</type><question> All of the following are examples of the cost of nonconformance EXCEPT?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Rework</option1><option2>Quality training</option2><option3>Scrap</option3><option4>Warranty costs</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp49</id><type>radio</type><question> A project manager has just been assigned to a project. The document that recognizes the existence of the project is called: </question><answer>3</answer><option1>The statement of work.</option1><option2>The project assignment.</option2><option3>The project charter.</option3><option4>The product description.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp50</id><type>radio</type><question> The WBS for the project represents:</question><answer>2</answer><option1>All the tangible items that must be delivered to the client.</option1><option2>All the work that must be completed for the project.</option2><option3>The work that must be performed by the project team.</option3><option4>All the activities of the project.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp51</id><type>radio</type><question> A manager that manages a group of related projects is called a:</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Project manager.</option1><option2>Project expediter.</option2><option3>Program coordinator.</option3><option4>Program manager.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp52</id><type>radio</type><question> A functional manager needs to communicate the needs of his or her personnel requirements and the utilization of each person as well as the assignments that they have in the future. To best accomplish this, what type of document should be used?</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Gantt chart</option1><option2>Network diagram</option2><option3>Staffing plan</option3><option4>Responsibility matrix</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp53</id><type>radio</type><question> A project manager is faced with making a decision about a risk that the team has identified. The risk involves the design of a bicycle. It has been found that the neck of the bicycle, where the steering bearing is located and the two supporting bars of the frame come together, will corrode in a high salt environment. If this takes place the neck may fail and injure the rider. The project team decides that the design of the bicycle should be modified by using corrosion resistant materials in the design of the neck. This will eliminate the risk from consideration. This technique is called:</question><answer>1</answer><option1>Risk avoidance.</option1><option2>Risk acceptance.</option2><option3>Risk rejection.</option3><option4>Risk deflection.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp54</id><type>radio</type><question> You are a project manager leading a cross-functional project team in a weak matrix environment. None of your project team members report to you functionally and you do not have the ability to directly reward their performance. The project is difficult, involving tight date constraints and challenging quality standards. Which of the following types of project management power will likely be the most effective in this circumstance?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Referent</option1><option2>Expert</option2><option3>Penalty</option3><option4>Formal</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp55</id><type>radio</type><question> If project A has a net present value (NPV) of U.S. $30,000 and project B has an NPV of U.S. $50,000, what is the opportunity cost if project B is selected?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>$23,000</option1><option2>$30,000</option2><option3>$20,000</option3><option4>$50,000</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp56</id><type>radio</type><question> The contingency budget will:</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Reduce the probability of scope changes.</option1><option2>Reduce the probability of cost overruns.</option2><option3>Increase the probability of a cost overrun.</option3><option4>Increase the probability of scope changes.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp57</id><type>radio</type><question> A project manager is quantifying risk for her project. Several of her experts are offsite, but wish to be included. How can this be done?</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Use Monte Carlo analysis using the Internet as a tool.</option1><option2>Apply the critical path method.</option2><option3>Determine options for recommended corrective action.</option3><option4>Apply the Delphi Technique.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp58</id><type>radio</type><question> What percentage of the total distribution are 3 sigma from the mean equal to? </question><answer>4</answer><option1>68.26%</option1><option2>99.99%</option2><option3>95.46%</option3><option4>99.73%</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp59</id><type>radio</type><question> A project manager holds the first risk meeting of the project team. The client is present at the meeting. At the meeting several risks are identified and assigned to members of the project team for evaluation and quantification. The result of the meeting is:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Expected value of the risk events.</option1><option2>Strategies for the risk events.</option2><option3>A list of potential risk events.</option3><option4>General statements about risks for the project.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp60</id><type>radio</type><question> A project manager is using weighted average duration estimates to perform schedule network analysis. Which type of mathematical analysis is being used?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Critical path method</option1><option2>PERT</option2><option3>Monte Carlo</option3><option4>Resource leveling</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp61</id><type>radio</type><question> An activity has an early start (ES) of day 3, a late start (LS) of day 13, an early finish (EF) of day g, and a late finish (LF) of day ig. The activity:</question><answer>4</answer><option1>is on the critical path.</option1><option2>has a lag.</option2><option3>is progressing well.</option3><option4>is not on the critical path.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp62</id><type>radio</type><question> Conflict resolution techniques that may be used on a project include confronting, smoothing, forcing and:</question><answer>1</answer><option1>withdrawing.</option1><option2>directing.</option2><option3>organizing.</option3><option4>controlling.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp63</id><type>radio</type><question> In the Monte Carlo technique, what is the criticality index?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>The number of days the project will be late divided by the project duration</option1><option2>The percent of time a given activity will be on the critical path</option2><option3>The percent of time an activity will be late</option3><option4>The sum of the duration of the critical path activities divided by the project expected value for duration</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp64</id><type>radio</type><question> Which phase of the project is likely to have the greatest amount of its funding spent?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Initiating</option1><option2>Executing</option2><option3>Planning</option3><option4>Closeout</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp65</id><type>radio</type><question> A control chart shows seven data points in a row on one side of the mean. What should be done?</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Perform a design of experiments.</option1><option2>Adjust the chart to reflect the new mean.</option2><option3>Find an assignable cause.</option3><option4>Nothing. This is the rule of seven and can be ignored.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp66</id><type>radio</type><question> The document that is proof of upper management.s commitment to the project and gives the authority to manage the project to the project manager is called:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>The project plan.</option1><option2>The project goals and objectives.</option2><option3>The project charter.</option3><option4>The project definition.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp67</id><type>radio</type><question> Which of the following represents the estimated value of the work actually accomplished?</question><answer>1</answer><option1>Earned value (EV)</option1><option2>Planned value (PV)</option2><option3>Actual cost (AC&apos;,</option3><option4>Cost variance (CV)</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp68</id><type>radio</type><question> A project manager is managing a project. The original scope baseline of the project was budgeted at $100,000. Since work on the project started there have been seventeen authorized and approved changes to the project. The changes have a value of $17,000 and the cost of investigating them prior to their approval was $2,500. What is the current budget for the project?</question><answer>4</answer><option1>$100,000</option1><option2>$114,500</option2><option3>$117,000</option3><option4>$119,500</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp69</id><type>radio</type><question> A project team has completed, and the customer has accepted, the completed project scope. However, the lessons learned required by the project management office have not been completed. What is the status of the project?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>The project is incomplete because the project needs to be re-planned.</option1><option2>The project is incomplete until all project and product deliverables are complete and accepted.</option2><option3>The project is complete because the customer has accepted the deliverables.</option3><option4>The project is complete because the project has reached the due date.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp70</id><type>radio</type><question> You are the project manager for a project that has high visibility. Your manager wants you to prepare a presentation for him to present at a conference. Most of the material in the presentation will be facts that are the results of your project. Your manager intends to present the material under his own name. Your name will not appear. What should you do?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Refuse to work on the presentation unless you are listed as a coauthor.</option1><option2>Do the work as you were told by your manager.</option2><option3>Present your own presentation.</option3><option4>Meet with your manager&apos;s manager and discuss the problem.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp71</id><type>radio</type><question> A project manager works in a company favoring the weakest authority for the project manager. The type of organization that holds the project manager to be the weakest is:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Projectized organization.</option1><option2>Strong matrix organization.</option2><option3>Weak matrix organization.</option3><option4>Balanced matrix.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp72</id><type>radio</type><question> A system development project is nearing project closing when a previously unidentified risk is discovered. This could potentially affect the project&apos;s overall ability to deliver. What should be done next?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Alert the project sponsor of potential impacts to cost, scope or schedule.</option1><option2>Qualify the risk.</option2><option3>Mitigate this risk by developing a risk response plan.</option3><option4>Develop a workaround.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp73</id><type>radio</type><question> You just found out that a major subcontractor for your project consistently provides deliverables late. The subcontractor approaches you and asks you to continue accepting late deliverables in exchange for a decrease in project costs. This offer is an example of:</question><answer>2</answer><option1>confronting.</option1><option2>compromise.</option2><option3>smoothing.</option3><option4>forcing.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp74</id><type>radio</type><question> Which of the following contains Change Management Plan ?</question><answer>1</answer><option1>Scope management plan</option1><option2>Communications management plan</option2><option3>Configuration management plan</option3><option4>Quality management plan</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp75</id><type>radio</type><question> You are managing a project in a just in time environment. This will require more attention, because the amount of inventory in such an environment is generally:</question><answer>4</answer><option1>45 percent.</option1><option2>lo percent.</option2><option3>12 percent.</option3><option4>o percent.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp76</id><type>radio</type><question> Resource leveling will generally:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Reduce the time needed to do the project.</option1><option2>Increase the total time necessary to do all the tasks.</option2><option3>Reduce the overutilization of resources.</option3><option4>Reduce resources to the lowest skill that is possible.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp77</id><type>radio</type><question> A task was scheduled to use two persons, full time, and take two weeks to complete. Instead, the project manager was only able to assign one person to this task. At the end of two weeks, the person assigned to the task was 75% complete. What is the cost performance index?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>0.75</option1><option2>1.50</option2><option3>0.25</option3><option4>1.15</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp78</id><type>radio</type><question> You are a project manager who was just assigned to take over a project from another project manager who is leaving the company. The previous project manager tells you that the project is on schedule, but only because he has constantly pushed the team to perform. What is the FIRST thing you should do as the new project manager?</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Check risk status.</option1><option2>Check cost performance.</option2><option3>Determine a management strategy.</option3><option4>Tell the team your objectives.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp79</id><type>radio</type><question> Which of the following is considered to be a simulation technique?</question><answer>3</answer><option1>PERT analysis</option1><option2>GERT analysis</option2><option3>Monte Carlo analysis</option3><option4>Critical path method</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp80</id><type>radio</type><question> Extensive use of ----- communication is most likely to aid in solving complex
problems.</question><answer>2</answer><option1>verbal</option1><option2>written</option2><option3>formal</option3><option4>nonverbal</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp81</id><type>radio</type><question> When checking the calendar of a team member to schedule a meeting, you see she has scheduled a meeting with a key stakeholder that you were not informed of. The best approach would be to:</question><answer>4</answer><option1>avoid mentioning it to the team member but continue to watch her activities.</option1><option2>notify your boss about the problem.</option2><option3>address the concern with the team member&apos;s boss.</option3><option4>address the concern with the team member.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp82</id><type>radio</type><question>Project A has an internal rate of return (IRR) of 21 percent. Project B has an IRR of 7 percent. Project C has an IRR of 31 percent. Project D has an IRR of ig percent. Which of these would be the BEST project?</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Project A</option1><option2>Project B</option2><option3>Project C</option3><option4>Project D</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp83</id><type>radio</type><question> The program evaluation and review technique (PERT) method of scheduling differs from the critical path method (CPM) because the PERT method:</question><answer>1</answer><option1>Uses weighted averages of activity durations to calculate project duration.</option1><option2>Uses ..dummy.. activities to represent logic ties.</option2><option3>Uses ..free float.. instead of ..total float.. in the schedule calculations.</option3><option4>Uses bar charts instead of logic diagrams to portray the schedule.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp84</id><type>radio</type><question> The key inputs to activity definition are: </question><answer>4</answer><option1>Work breakdown structure, the project schedule, and the network diagram.</option1><option2>Project schedule, progress reports, and change requests.</option2><option3>The project network diagram, constraints, and durations.</option3><option4>The work breakdown structure, the scope statement, and historical information that supports the applicable activity</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp85</id><type>radio</type><question> The customer requests a change to the project that would increase the project risk. Which of the following should you do before all the others?</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Include the expected monetary value of the risk in the new cost estimate.</option1><option2>Talk to the customer about the impact of the change.</option2><option3>Analyze the impacts of the change with the team.</option3><option4>Change the risk management plan.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp86</id><type>radio</type><question> An Ishikawa diagram helps to:</question><answer>13</answer><option1>put information in its order of priority</option1><option2>explore past outcomes.</option2><option3>show team responsibilities.</option3><option4>show functional responsibilities.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp87</id><type>radio</type><question> The lowest level at WBS is one of the following:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>The task.</option1><option2>The activity.</option2><option3>The work package.</option3><option4>The element.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp88</id><type>radio</type><question> A project manager would like to manage his project in such a way that he will be able to identify specific tasks that should be watched and managed more closely than others. The project manager should use which method?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>The PERT method</option1><option2>The critical path method</option2><option3>The GERT method</option3><option4>The PCDM method</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp89</id><type>radio</type><question> What characteristic best describes the cost baseline?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Total budget for the project</option1><option2>Time phased budget for the project</option2><option3>Total budget for the project including the contingency budget</option3><option4>Total budget for the project including the contingency budget and the management reserve</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp90</id><type>radio</type><question> In attempting to complete the project faster, the project manager looks at the cost associated with crashing each activity. The best approach to crashing would also include looking at the:</question><answer>1</answer><option1>risk impact of crashing each activity.</option1><option2>customer&apos;s opinion of which activities to crash.</option2><option3>boss&apos;s opinion of which activities to crash and in which order.</option3><option4>project life cycle phase in which the activity is due to occur.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp91</id><type>radio</type><question> A project manager has a problem with a team member&apos;s performance. What is best form of communication for addressing this problem?</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Formal written communication</option1><option2>Formal verbal communication</option2><option3>Informal written communication</option3><option4>Informal verbal communication</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp92</id><type>radio</type><question> Your employee is three days late with a report. Five minutes before the meeting where the topic of the report is to be discussed, she hands you the report. You notice some serious errors in it. What should you do?</question><answer>1</answer><option1>Cancel the meeting and reschedule when the report is fixed.</option1><option2>Go to the meeting and tell the other attendees there are errors in the report.</option2><option3>Force the employee to do the presentation and remain silent as the other attendees find the errors.</option3><option4>Cancel the meeting and rewrite the report yourself.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp93</id><type>radio</type><question> The act of doing anything that will help to bring future project performance into line with the project plan is called:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Budget update.</option1><option2>Revised cost estimate.</option2><option3>Corrective action.</option3><option4>Contingency planning.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp94</id><type>radio</type><question> A project is engaged in making electronic devices. It is necessary for them to purchase materials to make the printed circuit boards. All of the parts are common parts that are available from several vendors. The most likely contract that should be issued for these parts is:</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Unit price contract.</option1><option2>Firm fixed price contract.</option2><option3>Cost reimbursable contract.</option3><option4>Award fee contract.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp95</id><type>radio</type><question> You are the project manager for a large project that is completed on time and on budget. The customer and all of the stakeholders are pleased with the results. As a direct result of the successful completion of the project, your manager approves a bonus of $25,000 to you. There are fifteen members of the project team. One of the people on the project team has been a very low contributor to the project; the other fourteen have all been above standard. What should you do with the money?</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Keep the money yourself; you deserve it, and the manager gave it to you.</option1><option2>Divide the money equally among all the team members.</option2><option3>Ask the team members how they would divide the money.</option3><option4>Divide the money equally among the team members except for the substandard team member.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp96</id><type>radio</type><question> A project manager is using a cause and effect diagram with the team to determine how various factors might be linked to potential problems. In what part of the quality management process is the project manager involved?</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Quality analysis</option1><option2>Perform quality assurance</option2><option3>Perform quality control</option3><option4>Quality planning</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp97</id><type>radio</type><question> During which risk management process is a determination to transfer a risk made?</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Risk identification</option1><option2>Quantitative risk analysis</option2><option3>Risk response planning</option3><option4>Risk monitoring and control</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp98</id><type>radio</type><question> Your cost forecast shows that you will have a cost overrun at the end of the project. Which of the following should you do?</question><answer>1</answer><option1>Eliminate risks in estimates and re-estimate.</option1><option2>Meet with the sponsor to find out what work can be done sooner.</option2><option3>Cut quality.</option3><option4>Decrease scope.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp99</id><type>radio</type><question> At the request of the project team for a large project, the company.s purchasing department advertises that they intend to let a contract for construction work associated with the project. This is called:</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Procurement planning.</option1><option2>Solicitation.</option2><option3>Advertising.</option3><option4>The procurement process.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp100</id><type>radio</type><question> A project is considered complete when the :</question><answer>4</answer><option1>BAC is equal to the PV.</option1><option2>The EV is equal to the AC.</option2><option3>The PV is equal to the AC.</option3><option4>The BAC is equal to the EV.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp101</id><type>radio</type><question> A project is considered complete when the :</question><answer>4</answer><option1>BAC is equal to the PV.</option1><option2>The EV is equal to the AC.</option2><option3>The PV is equal to the AC.</option3><option4>The BAC is equal to the EV.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp102</id><type>radio</type><question> A particular stakeholder has a reputation for making many changes on projects. What is the best approach a project manager can take at the beginning of the project to manage this situation?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Say &quot;No&quot; to the stakeholder a few times to dissuade him from submitting more changes.</option1><option2>Get the stakeholder involved in the project as early as possible.</option2><option3>Talk to the stakeholder&apos;s boss to find ways to direct the stakeholder&apos;s activities to another project.</option3><option4>Ask that the stakeholder not be included in the stakeholder listing.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp103</id><type>radio</type><question> One of the things that the project manager will not have to worry about in preparing this estimate is:</question><answer>1</answer><option1>Activity listings.</option1><option2>Scaling the estimate.</option2><option3>Quantifying the estimate.</option3><option4>Historical support for the figures used</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp104</id><type>radio</type><question> A major negotiation with a potential subcontractor is scheduled for tomorrow when you discover there is a good chance the project will be cancelled. What should you do?</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Do not spend too much time preparing for the negotiations.</option1><option2>Cut the negotiations short.</option2><option3>Only negotiate major items.</option3><option4>Postpone the negotiations.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp105</id><type>radio</type><question> A project manager is preparing the budget for the project. There are several inputs to the budgeting process that the project manager will use. One of the things that the project manager will not use is the:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Cost estimates.</option1><option2>Project schedule.</option2><option3>Cost baseline.</option3><option4>Work breakdown structure.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp106</id><type>radio</type><question> The project status report is an example of which form of communication?</question><answer>1</answer><option1>Formal written communication</option1><option2>Formal verbal communication</option2><option3>Informal written communication</option3><option4>Informal verbal communication</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp107</id><type>radio</type><question> What are the major advantages of the functional type of organization?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Single point of contact for the customer</option1><option2>Stable organizational structure</option2><option3>Project orientation</option3><option4>Multifunctional teams are easy to form</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp108</id><type>radio</type><question> The project manager.s leadership style should be matched to the corresponding developmental level of the project team and should move through successive steps in the following order:</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Disciplinary, autocratic, participative.</option1><option2>Projectized, matrix, functional.</option2><option3>Team building, team development, responsibility assignment.</option3><option4>Directing, coaching, supporting, delegating.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp109</id><type>radio</type><question> In matrix management organizations, if the organization maintains many of the characteristics of the functional organization and the project managers are considered more like project coordinators or expediters, it is called a:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Strong matrix.</option1><option2>Project team.</option2><option3>Weak matrix.</option3><option4>Project office.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp110</id><type>radio</type><question> All of the following are part of the scope baseline EXCEPT the:</question><answer>1</answer><option1>project scope management plan.</option1><option2>project scope statement.</option2><option3>work breakdown structure.</option3><option4>work breakdown structure dictionary.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp111</id><type>radio</type><question> You are asked to select tools and techniques to implement a quality assurance program to supplement existing quality control activities. Which of the following would you choose?</question><answer>1</answer><option1>Quality audits</option1><option2>Statistical sampling</option2><option3>Pareto charts</option3><option4>Trend analysis</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp112</id><type>radio</type><question> The project manager is allocating overall cost estimates to individual activities to establish a baseline for measuring project performance. What process is this?</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Cost management</option1><option2>Cost estimating</option2><option3>Cost budgeting</option3><option4>Cost control</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp113</id><type>radio</type><question> During what part of the project management process is the project scope statement created?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Initiating</option1><option2>Planning</option2><option3>Executing</option3><option4>Monitoring and controlling</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp114</id><type>radio</type><question> One of the most important duties that the project manager can perform is the function of:</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Risk management.</option1><option2>Quality management.</option2><option3>Cost management.</option3><option4>Integration.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp115</id><type>radio</type><question> With a clear contract statement of work, a seller completes work as specified, but the buyer is not pleased with the results. The contract is considered to be:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>null and void.</option1><option2>incomplete.</option2><option3>complete.</option3><option4>waived.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp116</id><type>radio</type><question> The organization that is a formalized structure directed toward the support of the project community within the organization is called</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Matrix organization.</option1><option2>Project office.</option2><option3>Project team.</option3><option4>Project management office.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp117</id><type>radio</type><question> You have always been asked by your management to cut your project estimate by ten percent after you have given it to them. The scope of your new project is unclear and there are over 30 stakeholders. Management expects a 25 percent reduction in
downtime as a result of the project. Which of the following is the BEST course of action in this situation?</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Re-plan to achieve a 35 percent improvement in downtime.</option1><option2>Reduce the estimates and note the changes in the risk response plan.</option2><option3>Provide an accurate estimate of the actual costs and be able to support it.</option3><option4>Meet with the team to identify where you can find lo percent savings.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp118</id><type>radio</type><question> Which of the following is the best project management tool to use to determine the longest time the project will take?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>WBS</option1><option2>Network diagram</option2><option3>Bar chart</option3><option4>Project charter</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp119</id><type>radio</type><question> In a large organization a project expediter is being used to manage a project for an important client. The position of project expediter would be found in what kind of an organization?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Strong matrix</option1><option2>Weak matrix</option2><option3>Functional</option3><option4>Projectized</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp120</id><type>radio</type><question> Herzberg divided motivation factors into two classes: satisfiers and dissatisfiers. Examples of satisfiers are:</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Vacation time, assignment of a personal staff assistant.</option1><option2>Work satisfaction, fringe benefits.</option2><option3>Plush office space, performance based salary raise.</option3><option4>Sense of personal achievement, work satisfaction.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp121</id><type>radio</type><question> The project sponsor has just provided the preliminary project scope statement. What is the NEXT thing to do? </question><answer>4</answer><option1>Begin to complete work packages</option1><option2>Complete scope verification</option2><option3>Start integrated change control</option3><option4>Start to create management plans</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp122</id><type>radio</type><question> Two people are arguing about what needs to be done to complete a work package. if the project manager wants to know what is going on, she should pay MOST attention to:</question><answer>4</answer><option1>what is being said and when.</option1><option2>what is being said, who is saying it, and the time of day.</option2><option3>physical mannerisms and what is being said.</option3><option4>the pitch and tone of the voices, and physical mannerisms.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp123</id><type>radio</type><question> The skill of listening involves more than just hearing the sounds. One of the characteristics of a good listener is that he or she:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Finishes the speaker.s sentences.</option1><option2>Takes good notes.</option2><option3>Repeats some of the things said.</option3><option4>Agrees with the speaker.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp124</id><type>radio</type><question> A manufacturing project has a schedule performance index (SPI) of 0.89 and a cost
performance index (CPI) of 0.91. Generally, what is the best explanation for why this occurred?</question><answer>4</answer><option1>The scope was changed.</option1><option2>A supplier went out of business and a new one needed to be found.</option2><option3>Additional equipment needed to be purchased.</option3><option4>A critical path activity took longer and needed more labor hours to complete.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp125</id><type>radio</type><question> The new software installation project is in progress. The project manager is working with the quality assurance department to improve everyone&apos;s confidence that the project will satisfy the quality standards. Which of the following MUST they have
before they start this process?</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Quality problems</option1><option2>Quality improvement</option2><option3>Quality control measurements</option3><option4>Rework</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp126</id><type>radio</type><question>The project is not completed until:</question><answer>2</answer><option1>the project scope is completed, administrative closure is completed and payment is received.</option1><option2>formal acceptance is received, and any other requirements for project closure as stated in the contract are met.</option2><option3>the customer is satisfied and final payment is received.</option3><option4>lessons learned are completed.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp127</id><type>radio</type><question> Primary outputs from team development are:</question><answer>1</answer><option1>Input to performance appraisals.</option1><option2>High project team morale.</option2><option3>Reduced project cost.</option3><option4>Greater customer satisfaction.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp128</id><type>radio</type><question> All of the following are the responsibility of a project manager EXCEPT?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Maintain the confidentiality of customer confidential information.</option1><option2>Determine the legality of company procedures.</option2><option3>Ensure that a conflict of interest does not compromise the legitimate interest of the customer.</option3><option4>Provide accurate and truthful represeqtations in cost estimates.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp129</id><type>radio</type><question> One of the mandatory things that a project manager must have in order to have good team building is:</question><answer>1</answer><option1>Commitment from top level management.</option1><option2>Co-location of team members.</option2><option3>Establishment of clear negotiated goals.</option3><option4>Open discussion of poor individual performance.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp130</id><type>radio</type><question> A project manager for the seller is told by her management that the project should do whatever possible to be awarded incentive money. The primary objective of incentive clauses in a contract is to:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>reduce costs for the buyer.</option1><option2>help the seller control costs.</option2><option3>synchronize objectives.</option3><option4>reduce risk for the seller by shifting risk to the buyer.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp131</id><type>radio</type><question> A project manager is managing a project where there will be a number of persons working together. She wants to enhance the ability of the team to work together and perform as a team. One of the things that she can do to maximize the ability of the team to do this is:</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Cohabitation.</option1><option2>Co-location.</option2><option3>Staffing plan.</option3><option4>Work breakdown structure.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp132</id><type>radio</type><question> A project manager will manage a large complicated project that is located in a remote part of Africa. The project will last for five years and will have the product of producing a nuclear reactor that will generate 900 megawatts of power at start-up. The best kind of organization for managing this project is:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Strong matrix management.</option1><option2>Weak matrix management.</option2><option3>Projectized organization.</option3><option4>Functional organization.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp133</id><type>radio</type><question> During project executing, a team member comes to the project manager because he is not sure of what work he needs to accomplish on the project. Which of the following documents contain detailed descriptions of work packages?</question><answer>1</answer><option1>Work breakdown structure (WBS) dictionary</option1><option2>Activity list</option2><option3>Preliminary project scope statement</option3><option4>Project scope management plan</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp134</id><type>radio</type><question> According to McGregor.s concept of theory X and theory Y, which of
the following statements is true?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Theory Y managers view their subordinates as lazy, irresponsible, and resistant to change.</option1><option2>Theory Y managers view their subordinates as creative, imaginative,and agreeable to change.</option2><option3>Theory X managers tend to delegate authority.</option3><option4>McGregor did not conceive of theory X and theory Y.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp135</id><type>radio</type><question> You are asked to prepare a budget for completing a project that was started last
year and then shelved for six months. All the following would be included in the
budget except ?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Fixed costs</option1><option2>Sunk costs</option2><option3>Direct costs</option3><option4>Variable costs</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp136</id><type>radio</type><question> You have just been assigned as project manager for a large manufacturing project. This one-year project is about halfway done. It involves five different sellers and 20 members of your company on the project team. You want to quickly review where the project now stands. Which of the following reports would be the most helpful in finding such information?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Work status</option1><option2>Progress</option2><option3>Forecast</option3><option4>Communications</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp137</id><type>radio</type><question> The customer on a project tells the project manager he has run out of money to pay for the project. What should the project manager do first?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Shift more of the work to later in the schedule to allow time for the customer to get the funds.</option1><option2>Enter administrative closure.</option2><option3>Stop work.</option3><option4>Release part of the project team.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp138</id><type>radio</type><question> Which of the following is true of management by objectives (MBO)?</question><answer>4</answer><option1>The supervisor establishes performance objectives.</option1><option2>The supervisor sets the general objectives and the subordinate reviews and agrees to them.</option2><option3>Objectives do not need to be quantifiable.</option3><option4>The supervisor and the employee jointly establish performance objectives.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp139</id><type>radio</type><question> The Monte Carlo technique can be used to:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Determine the amount of contingency budget needed for the project.</option1><option2>Determine the amount of the management reserve.</option2><option3>Determine the criticality index for an activity in the schedule.</option3><option4>Determine the risk index for a risk in the project.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp140</id><type>radio</type><question> A project manager has been overwhelmed with problems on his project. He would like to identify the root cause of the problems in order to determine where to focus his attention. Which of the following tools would be BEST for the project manager to use?</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Pareto chart</option1><option2>Conflict resolution techniques</option2><option3>Fishbone diagram</option3><option4>Trend analysis</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp141</id><type>radio</type><question> The client demands changes to the product specification that will add only two weeks to the critical path. Which of the following is the best thing for the project manager to do?</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Compress the schedule to recover the two weeks.</option1><option2>Cut scope to recover the two weeks.</option2><option3>Consult with the sponsor before taking any action.</option3><option4>Advise the client of the impact of the change.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp142</id><type>radio</type><question> Lag means:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>the amount of time an activity can be delayed without delaying the project finish date.</option1><option2>the amount of time an activity can be delayed without delaying the early start date of its successor.</option2><option3>waiting time.</option3><option4>the product of a forward and backward pass.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp143</id><type>radio</type><question> A routine audit of a cost reimbursable (CR) contract determines that overcharges are being made. If the contract does not specify corrective action, the buyer should:</question><answer>1</answer><option1>continue to make project payments.</option1><option2>halt payments until the problem is corrected.</option2><option3>void the contract and start legal action to recover overpayments.</option3><option4>change the contract to require more frequent audits.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp144</id><type>radio</type><question> A project manager is in the middle of the executing process of a verylarge construction project when he discovers that the time needed to complete the project is longer than the time available. What is the BEST thing to do?</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Cut product scope.</option1><option2>Meet with management and tell them that the required date cannot be met.</option2><option3>Work overtime.</option3><option4>Determine options for schedule compression and present management with your recommended option.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp145</id><type>radio</type><question> You are a new project manager who has never managed a project before. You have been asked to plan a new project. It would be BEST in this situation to rely on during planning in order to improve your chance of success.</question><answer>3</answer><option1>your intuition and training</option1><option2>stakeholder analysis</option2><option3>historical information</option3><option4>configuration management</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp146</id><type>radio</type><question> During the project life cycle, in which part of the life cycle will risk be the lowest?</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Initiation</option1><option2>Planning</option2><option3>Execution</option3><option4>Closeout</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp147</id><type>radio</type><question> A project manager is managing a project where a risk occurs. There is no plan to respond to this risk. The response to a negative risk event that has no plan is called:</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Repair order.</option1><option2>Workaround.</option2><option3>Risk mitigation.</option3><option4>Risk deflection.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp148</id><type>radio</type><question> A project manager is dealing with risk analysis on a software development project. There is a risk that the module that creates the most important report that the system will create will not work properly and will require 200 person-hours to correct. The project manager decides to do nothing about this risk. Which of the following risk strategies is the project manager employing?</question><answer>1</answer><option1>Acceptance</option1><option2>Avoidance</option2><option3>Mitigation</option3><option4>Deflection</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp149</id><type>radio</type><question> A trucking company expects to purchase 525 truck tires over the next year for their fleet. The company places a blanket order for the tires to a local tire vendor. At the end of a year the company has only purchased 500 of the tires. What should be done to close the contract?</question><answer>1</answer><option1>The trucking company should pay for the 25 tires and the tire vendor should deliver them.</option1><option2>The total price of the blanket order should be adjusted.</option2><option3>The contract should be closed because the year is up and no adjustments are necessary.</option3><option4>A new blanket order should be negotiated.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp150</id><type>radio</type><question> You are the project manager for a large project under contract with the government. The contract for this two year, multi-million dollar project was signed six months ago. You were not involved in contract negotiations or setting up procedures for
managing changes, but now you are swamped with changes from the customer and from people inside your organization. Who is normally responsible for formally reviewing major changes to the projectlcontract?</question><answer>1</answer><option1>The change control board</option1><option2>The contractingllegal department</option2><option3>The project manager</option3><option4>Senior management</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp151</id><type>radio</type><question> Which of the following media can a communicator use to present information?</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Visual</option1><option2>Audio and visual</option2><option3>Tactile</option3><option4>Visual, audio, and tactile</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp152</id><type>radio</type><question> A project manager managing any project should perform risk analysis at what stage of the project:</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Just before any major meeting with the client.</option1><option2>On a regular basis throughout the project.</option2><option3>Only when justified by the awareness of new risks becoming a possibility.</option3><option4>When preparing the project plan.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp153</id><type>radio</type><question> Lessons learned are BEST completed by:</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Project manager</option1><option2>Team</option2><option3>Sponsor</option3><option4>Stakeholders</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp154</id><type>radio</type><question> The processes required to ensure that the project will satisfy the needs for which it was undertaken include all activities of the overall management function that determines the quality policy, objectives, and responsibilities and implements them by means such as quality planning, quality control, quality assurance, and quality improvement, within the quality system. This is called:</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Quality assurance.</option1><option2>Quality control.</option2><option3>Quality planning.</option3><option4>Quality management.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp155</id><type>radio</type><question> According to Deming and Juran most of the quality problems that exist are due to a defect or failure in processes that are controlled by:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>The project manager.</option1><option2>The procurement manager.</option2><option3>Upper management.</option3><option4>Stakeholders.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp156</id><type>radio</type><question> Work results, quality checklists, operational definitions, and the management plan are:</question><answer>1</answer><option1>Inputs to quality control.</option1><option2>Outputs from quality control.</option2><option3>Inputs to quality assurance.</option3><option4>Outputs from quality assurance.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp157</id><type>radio</type><question> The primary benefits of meeting quality requirements are:</question><answer>1</answer><option1>Cost and delays are reduced, production improves, cost to customer goes up, and profits go up.</option1><option2>Cost and delays are reduced, production improves, market share increases, and profits go up.</option2><option3>Cost and delays are reduced, capital expenditures go down, market share increases, and profits go up.</option3><option4>Cost and delays are reduced, production improves, market share increases, and profits are maintained.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp158</id><type>radio</type><question> Project quality assurance:</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Includes policing the conformance of the project team to specs.</option1><option2>Provides the project team and stakeholders with standards, by which the project performance is measured.</option2><option3>Is a managerial process that defines the organization, design, resources, and objectives of quality management.</option3><option4>Provides confidence that the project will satisfy relevant quality standards.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp159</id><type>radio</type><question> The primary objective of contract negotiations is to:</question><answer>2</answer><option1>get the most from the other side.</option1><option2>protect the relationship.</option2><option3>get the highest monetary return.</option3><option4>define objectives and stick to them.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp160</id><type>radio</type><question> The ISO 9000: 2000 standard is used to:</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Formalize the tools of quality management.</option1><option2>Set international standards for quality conformance in organizations.</option2><option3>Set USA national standards for quality conformance in organizations.</option3><option4>Develop standards of excellence for manufacturing facilities.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp161</id><type>radio</type><question> A project is facing a major change to its project deliverables. If the project manager is involved in determining which quality standards are relevant to the change, the project manager must be involved in:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>quality management.</option1><option2>perform quality assurance.</option2><option3>quality planning.</option3><option4>perform quality control.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp162</id><type>radio</type><question> What does ..cost of acceptance.. mean?</question><answer>3</answer><option1>The cost of establishing and maintaining the quality function</option1><option2>The life cycle cost of the project</option2><option3>The cost of inspection and reinspection, quality assurance, quality management, and quality planning</option3><option4>The cost of meeting project objectives</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp163</id><type>radio</type><question> In which project management process group is the detailed project budget created? </question><answer>3</answer><option1>Initiating</option1><option2>Before the project management process</option2><option3>Planning</option3><option4>Executing</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp164</id><type>radio</type><question> Rearranging resources so that a constant number of resources is used each month is called:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>crashing.</option1><option2>floating.</option2><option3>leveling.</option3><option4>fast tracking.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp165</id><type>radio</type><question> In the Shewhart and Deming cycle, the letters P D C A stand for:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Purchase, deliver, cost, and acquisition.</option1><option2>Prevent defects caused by anyone.</option2><option3>Plan, do, check, and act.</option3><option4>Please don.t cause accidents.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp166</id><type>radio</type><question> A project manager must make a narrative description of the project. This narrative description covers the items that will be supplied under the contract with the client. It is called:</question><answer>2</answer><option1>The project plan.</option1><option2>The statement of work.</option2><option3>The exception report.</option3><option4>The progress report.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp167</id><type>radio</type><question> The project manager is considering contracting some of the work of the project to a service bureau. The service bureau has been used in the past by this project manager. The manager has several choices of contracts that can be used to subcontract this work. Which of the following is not a type of contract that the project manager might choose?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Firm fixed price</option1><option2>Make or buy</option2><option3>Cost plus incentive fee</option3><option4>Unit price</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp168</id><type>radio</type><question> Bidder conferences are part of:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>plan contracting.</option1><option2>contract administration.</option2><option3>request seller responses.</option3><option4>plan purchases and acquisitions.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp169</id><type>radio</type><question> The three principal interests in maintaining good document control are:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Timely communication, collection of performance appraisal data,
and assuring proper disposal of sensitive documents.</option1><option2>Timely communication, maintaining proper approvals, and communication
cost control.</option2><option3>Effective communication, ability to reconstruct why decisions were
made, and historical value.</option3><option4>Security, change management, and procedural documentation.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp170</id><type>radio</type><question> The use of brainstorming as a communications technique encourages which of the following?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Team building and convergent thinking</option1><option2>Divergent thinking</option2><option3>Analytical results</option3><option4>Use of the scientific method</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp171</id><type>radio</type><question> Which of the following techniques allows for the participants to be anonymous?</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Brain washing</option1><option2>Nominal group</option2><option3>Delphi technique</option3><option4>Crawford slip</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp172</id><type>radio</type><question> In the communications model, communications between the sender and the receiver often are affected by communications barriers. These include all of the following except:</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Cultural differences.</option1><option2>Differences in motivation.</option2><option3>Educational differences.</option3><option4>Lack of a communications device.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp173</id><type>radio</type><question> The project status meeting is not going well. Everyone is talking at the same time, there are people who are not participating and many topics are being discussed at random. Which of the following rules for effective meetings is not being adhered to?</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Demonstrate courtesy and consideration of each other, control who is allowed to speak.</option1><option2>Schedule meetings in advance.</option2><option3>Have a purpose for the meeting, with the right people in attendance.</option3><option4>Create and publish an agenda and a set of rules for controlling the meeting.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp174</id><type>radio</type><question> The project manager has a very complex communication to prepare for the program manager. In order to ensure that the communication will be understood as completely as possible, what method of communication should be used?</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Oral</option1><option2>Written</option2><option3>Nonverbal</option3><option4>Oral, written, and nonverbal</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp175</id><type>radio</type><question> Formal acceptance by the client or the sponsor of the project indicates that they have accepted the products of the project. This document should be signed off during what part of the project?</question><answer>1</answer><option1>Administrative closure</option1><option2>As the last task in the project plan</option2><option3>After the project is closed out</option3><option4>When requested by the program manager</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp176</id><type>radio</type><question> A project manager has six people in a team. It is important that each of them communicates information to each of the others. How many lines of communication are there in this group of people?</question><answer>1</answer><option1>Fifteen</option1><option2>Twenty-one</option2><option3>Seven</option3><option4>Six</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp177</id><type>radio</type><question> A project manager is considering how her time is being spent in the project. One of the things that concerns her is how much time she will be spending communicating. The percent of time that is generally spent communicating by project managers is:</question><answer>4</answer><option1>10 percent.</option1><option2>20 percent.</option2><option3>50 percent.</option3><option4>90 percent.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp178</id><type>radio</type><question> What is one of the KEY objectives during negotiations?</question><answer>1</answer><option1>Obtain a fair and reasonable price.</option1><option2>Negotiate a price under the seller&apos;s estimate.</option2><option3>Ensure that all project risks are thoroughly delineated.</option3><option4>Ensure that an effective communications management plan is established.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp179</id><type>radio</type><question> The three main types of communication are:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>written, oral, and graphic.</option1><option2>written, oral, and visual.</option2><option3>verbal, written, and electronic.</option3><option4>verbal, formal documentation, and informal documentation.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp180</id><type>radio</type><question> You are the project manager for a high visibility project. The margin on this project is low, and it is extremely important that the cost estimates for the work on the project be accurate. While reviewing the cost estimates for this project you notice that one of the cost estimates for an element in the WBS is 10% higher than two previous projects for very similar work. What 
should you do ?</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Accept the estimate because you trust all of the people on your project team, and they are responsible for estimates.</option1><option2>Reduce the estimate and add the additional budget to the management reserve.</option2><option3>Ask the person responsible for the estimate to explain the difference and bring supporting information to you.</option3><option4>Reduce the estimate and add the additional budget to the contingency reserve.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp181</id><type>radio</type><question> The float of an activity is determined by:</question><answer>4</answer><option1>performing a Monte Carlo analysis.</option1><option2>the waiting time between activities.</option2><option3>determining lag.</option3><option4>determining the amount of time the activity can be delayed before it delays the critical path.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp182</id><type>radio</type><question> Linear programming is an example of what type of project selection criteria?</question><answer>1</answer><option1>Constrained optimization</option1><option2>Comparative approach</option2><option3>Benefit measurement</option3><option4>Impact analysis</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp183</id><type>radio</type><question> You are the manager of a research group that is developing a new chemical material. You hire a person from a competing company who has a great deal of expertise in this area. The person contributes greatly to the progress of your project. During conversations with the person you determine that many of this person.s ideas were developed by the competing company. What do you do?</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Tell the person that he or she should not mention that the ideas came from another company.</option1><option2>Sign a nondisclosure agreement with this person before he or she leaves your company.</option2><option3>Accept the new ideas.</option3><option4>Investigate the employee for security reasons.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp184</id><type>radio</type><question> The project life cycle differs from the product life cycle in that the project life cycle:</question><answer>2</answer><option1>does not incorporate a methodology.</option1><option2>is different for each industry.</option2><option3>can spawn many projects.</option3><option4>describes project management activities.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp185</id><type>radio</type><question> A manager and the head of engineering discuss a change to a major work package. After the meeting, the manager contacts you and tells you to complete the paperwork to make the change. This is an example of:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>management attention to scope management.</option1><option2>management planning.</option2><option3>a project expediter position.</option3><option4>a change control system.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp186</id><type>radio</type><question> A team member notifies the project manager that the activities comprising a work package are no longer appropriate. It would be BEST for the project manager to be in what part of the project management process?</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Corrective action</option1><option2>Integrated change control</option2><option3>Monitoring and controlling</option3><option4>Project closing</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp187</id><type>radio</type><question> A project is plagued by changes to the project charter. Who has the primary responsibility to decide if these changes are necessary?</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Project manager</option1><option2>Project team</option2><option3>Sponsor</option3><option4>Stakeholders</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp188</id><type>radio</type><question> All of the following are parts of direct and manage project execution except?</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Identifying changes</option1><option2>Using a work breakdown structure</option2><option3>Implementing corrective actions</option3><option4>Setting up a project control system</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp189</id><type>radio</type><question> During a project team meeting, a team member suggests an enhancement to the scope that is beyond the scope of the project charter. The project manager points out that the team needs to concentrate on completing all the work and only the work required. This is an example of:</question><answer>2</answer><option1>change management process.</option1><option2>scope management.</option2><option3>quality analysis.</option3><option4>scope decomposition.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp190</id><type>radio</type><question> During activity definition, a team member identifies an activity that needs to be accomplished. However, another team member believes that the activity is not part of the project as he interprets the project scope statement. What is the thing for
the project manager to do?</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Try to build a consensus of the team.</option1><option2>Make the decision himself.</option2><option3>Ask the sponsor for clarification.</option3><option4>Ask senior management for clarification.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp191</id><type>radio</type><question> A new project manager has asked you for advice on creating a work breakdown structure. After you explain the process to him, he asks you what software he should use to create the WBS and what should he do with it when he is finished creating it. You might respond that it is not the picture that is the most valuable result of creating a WBS. It is:</question><answer>2</answer><option1>a bar chart.</option1><option2>team buy-in.</option2><option3>activities.</option3><option4>a list of risks.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp192</id><type>radio</type><question> In a fixed price (FP) contract, the fee or profit is:</question><answer>1</answer><option1>unknown.</option1><option2>part of the negotiation involved in paying every invoice.</option2><option3>applied as a line item to every invoice.</option3><option4>determined with the other party at the end of the project.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp193</id><type>radio</type><question> If the optimistic estimate for an activity is 12 days, and the pessimistic estimate is 18 days, what is the standard deviation of this activity? </question><answer>1</answer><option1>1</option1><option2>1.3</option2><option3>6</option3><option4>3</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp194</id><type>radio</type><question> If a project has a 60 percent chance of a U.S. $1oo,ooop profit and a 40 percent chance
of a U.S. $1oo,ooo loss, the expected monetary value for the project is:</question><answer>3</answer><option1>$1oo,ooo profit</option1><option2>$60,000 loss</option2><option3>$20,000 profit</option3><option4>$40,000 loss</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp195</id><type>radio</type><question> The precedence diagramming method (activity-on-node) is different from the arrow diagramming method (activity-on-arrow) because a precedence diagram:</question><answer>2</answer><option1>can use PERT.</option1><option2>has four relationships among activities.</option2><option3>has only finish-to-finish relationships.</option3><option4>may use dummy activities.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp196</id><type>radio</type><question> During project executing, a large number of changes are made to the project. The project manager should:</question><answer>2</answer><option1>wait until all changes are known and print out a new schedule.</option1><option2>make approved changes as needed, but retain the schedule baseline.</option2><option3>make only the changes approved by management.</option3><option4>talk to management before any changes are made.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp197</id><type>radio</type><question> One common way to compute estimate at completion (EAC) is to take the budget at
completion (BAC) and:</question><answer>4</answer><option1>divide by SPI.</option1><option2>multiply by SPI.</option2><option3>multiply by CPI.</option3><option4>divide by CPI.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp198</id><type>radio</type><question> Assuming that the ends of a range of estimates are +/- 3 sigma from the mean, which
of the following range estimates involves the LEAST risk?</question><answer>3</answer><option1>30 days, plus or minus 5 days</option1><option2>22-30 days</option2><option3>Optimistic = 26 days, most likely = 30 days, pessimistic = 33 days</option3><option4>Mean of 28 days</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp199</id><type>radio</type><question> A project performed under a cost reimbursable contract has finally entered the closing process. What must the buyer remember to do?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Decrease the risk rating of the project.</option1><option2>Audit seller&apos;s cost submittals.</option2><option3>Evaluate the fee he is paying.</option3><option4>Make sure that the seller is not adding resources.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp200</id><type>radio</type><question> A large, complex construction project in a foreign country requires coordination to move the required equipment through crowded city streets. To ensure the equipment is transported successfully, your contact in that country informs you that you will have to pay the local police a fee for coordinating traffic. What should you do?</question><answer>3</answer><option1>Do not pay the fee because it is a bribe.</option1><option2>Eliminate the work.</option2><option3>Pay the fee.</option3><option4>Do not pay the fee if it is not part of the project estimate.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp201</id><type>radio</type><question> A major negotiation with a potential subcontractor is scheduled for tomorrow when you discover there is a good chance the project will be cancelled. What should you do?</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Do not spend too much time preparing for the negotiations.</option1><option2>Cut the negotiations short.</option2><option3>Only negotiate major items.</option3><option4>Postpone the negotiations.</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp202</id><type>radio</type><question> Which of the following is NOT an input to the initiating process group?</question><answer>4</answer><option1>Company processes</option1><option2>The company culture</option2><option3>Historical WBSs</option3><option4>Project scope statement</option4></quiz>
<quiz><id>pmp203</id><type>radio</type><question> A project manager does not have much time to spend planning before the mandatory start date arrives. He therefore wants to move through planning as effectively as possible. Which of the following would you recommend?</question><answer>2</answer><option1>Make sure you have a completed preliminary project scope statement and then start the WBS.</option1><option2>Create an activity list before creating a network diagram.</option2><option3>Document all the known risks before you document the high-level assumptions.</option3><option4>Finalize the quality management plan before you determine quality metrics.</option4></quiz>
<quiz_level><!--204-->